<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Justin Bush</title>
    <link>https://www.justinmbush.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Justin Bush</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 08:23:34 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.justinmbush.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Drone</title>
      <link>https://www.justinmbush.com/posts/drone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 09:04:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.justinmbush.com/posts/drone/</guid>
      <description>Continuous Integration Before I even start writing any code, I wanted to start off with a CI/CD tool. After doing some research, I have landed on using Drone. At first, I will only be using Drone for continuous integration while developing, but will eventually use it for deploying into my &amp;ldquo;production&amp;rdquo; system.
IaC All The Things With this project, I want to start everything right away with defining all infrastructure as code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Things First</title>
      <link>https://www.justinmbush.com/posts/first-things-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 07:54:19 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.justinmbush.com/posts/first-things-first/</guid>
      <description>Containerize It Now that I have a basic Idea of what I want to build, it&amp;rsquo;s time to dive in.
The very first thing that I want to do is create a Phoenix app and throw it in a Docker container. After creating the Phoenix app by following their getting started guide, I created the following Dockerfile:
FROMelixir:latestRUN apt-get update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; \  apt-get install -y postgresql-clientRUN mkdir /appCOPY ./remote_coach /appWORKDIR/appRUN mix local.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting a New Project</title>
      <link>https://www.justinmbush.com/posts/starting-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 07:16:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.justinmbush.com/posts/starting-project/</guid>
      <description>Time To Play Around For a while, I&amp;rsquo;ve been messing around here and there with different things that have caught my interest. It mostly ends up with me going through &amp;ldquo;getting started&amp;rdquo; guides and reading documentation. While it&amp;rsquo;s something, it&amp;rsquo;s usually not enough to get any depth of knowledge in the subject and I end up forgetting most of it in a couple of months.
So, for quite some time I have been trying to figure out a project to start on that would help me gain more experience in these tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hi! I&#39;m Justin Bush</title>
      <link>https://www.justinmbush.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 08:23:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.justinmbush.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a Software Engineer from Salt Lake City, UT I am passionate about software that is actually what the customer wants and needs. To me, this means building software and architectures that are easily tested and deployed. This also means creating feedback loops and data from the customers as well as within the software process.
Currently, I am at MasterControl on the &amp;ldquo;System Team&amp;rdquo; working on the CI/CD Pipeline.
I Graduated from the University of Utah in 2018 with a Bachelor of Science in Computer Science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>https://www.justinmbush.com/posts/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 15:17:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.justinmbush.com/posts/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Hi there! Welcome to my first post.
This is the start of a new adventure in building some stuff and writing about it.
Finding Passion For the last little while since I have been out of school and have started working in a &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; job, I have been trying to figure out my place in this world of software. I guess in reflection, I&amp;rsquo;ve been searching for what I am actually passionate about.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>