<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Posts on Justin Bush</title>
		<link>https://www.justinmbush.com/posts/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Posts on Justin Bush</description>
		<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 07:16:55 -0700</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://www.justinmbush.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
		<item>
			<title>Starting a New Project</title>
			<link>https://www.justinmbush.com/posts/starting-project/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 07:16:55 -0700</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://www.justinmbush.com/posts/starting-project/</guid>
			<description>Time To Play Around For a while, I&amp;rsquo;ve been messing around here and there with different things that have caught my interest. It mostly ends up with me going through &amp;ldquo;getting started&amp;rdquo; guides and reading documentation. While it&amp;rsquo;s something, it&amp;rsquo;s usually not enough to get any depth of knowledge in the subject and I end up forgetting most of it in a couple of months.
So, for quite some time I have been trying to figure out a project to start on that would help me gain more experience in these tools.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="time-to-play-around">Time To Play Around</h3>
<p>For a while, I&rsquo;ve been messing around here and there with different things that have caught my interest.
It mostly ends up with me going through &ldquo;getting started&rdquo; guides and reading documentation.
While it&rsquo;s something, it&rsquo;s usually not enough to get any depth of knowledge in the subject and I end up forgetting most of it in a couple of months.</p>
<p>So, for quite some time I have been trying to figure out a project to start on that would help me gain more experience in these tools.
The problem was that I felt like I didn&rsquo;t have any good ideas.
But really, I just didn&rsquo;t have the <em>perfect</em> idea.</p>
<p>I wanted to build something that was:</p>
<ul>
<li>useful</li>
<li>interesting</li>
<li>needed to be &ldquo;scalable&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
<p>Now that last item was the trickiest.
See, most applications don&rsquo;t require that last bit without a ton of users.
So at first it was hard to justify the complex architecture just for a web app that one person will use, but today I&rsquo;ve decided to hell with justification, let&rsquo;s just build a cool thing in the way I want to build it.</p>
<h3 id="things-i-want-to-use">Things I Want To Use</h3>
<p>For this project, the fancy tools and technologies I want to use to begin with are the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Elixir / Phoenix</li>
<li>Kubernetes</li>
<li>Kafka (or some other messaging/streaming queue)</li>
<li>Istio (or some other service mesh)</li>
<li>Prometheus / FluentD / Jaeger</li>
<li>Whatever other &ldquo;cloud native&rdquo; things strikes my fancy</li>
</ul>
<p>My plan is to start off with a mostly &ldquo;monolithic&rdquo; application, break it apart when it seems to make sense, and then introduce these things in the order I&rsquo;ve put above.</p>
<h3 id="the-idea">The Idea</h3>
<p><em>drumroll</em></p>
<p>Remote coaching video analysis.</p>
<p>The idea is something that I have wanted for myself when working with my olympic weightlifting coach.
For the most part, when training, I am by myself and I send him videos remotely.
He then analyzes the video and sends me some critique and help with my form.
The problem is that we mostly do this over text and it&rsquo;s hard to go back and reference past videos to see how I&rsquo;ve been improving.</p>
<p>Now, I will be doing some discovery in the next little while, but the general idea will be:</p>
<ul>
<li>upload a video</li>
<li>tag it with what type of movement it is (i.e. Hang Snatch)</li>
<li>get a response from the coach in either text or a video analysis from something like Coach&rsquo;s Eye</li>
</ul>
<p>The tagging will be great to be able to look through videos of the same movement to see progression over time or areas that need work on.
This might also be great for a &ldquo;team&rdquo; where there is a common place for everyone on the team to post their videos and get feedback in a place where the rest of the team can see.
This would make the remote team trainings feel a little bit more connected. (Especially if the team is doing similar movements in the same cycle)</p>
<p>With this new project, I will be posting articles about the things I am working.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>First Post</title>
			<link>https://www.justinmbush.com/posts/first-post/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 15:17:38 -0700</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://www.justinmbush.com/posts/first-post/</guid>
			<description>Hi there! Welcome to my first post.
This is the start of a new adventure in building some stuff and writing about it.
Finding Passion For the last little while since I have been out of school and have started working in a &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; job, I have been trying to figure out my place in this world of software. I guess in reflection, I&amp;rsquo;ve been searching for what I am actually passionate about.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi there! Welcome to my first post.</p>
<p>This is the start of a new adventure in building some stuff and writing about it.</p>
<h3 id="finding-passion">Finding Passion</h3>
<p>For the last little while since I have been out of school and have started working in a &ldquo;real&rdquo; job, I have been trying to figure out my place in this world of software.
I guess in reflection, I&rsquo;ve been searching for what I am actually passionate about.
In school I was incredibly interested in compilers, programming languages, and operating systems.
After being in the industry, I am still interested in those topics, but other things have caught my eye.
I am now incredibly fascinated with the idea of building highly-scalable, cloud-based software that can be deployed easily and focuses on the customer.</p>
<h3 id="first-team">First Team</h3>
<p>The first team that I was on in MasterControl was a &ldquo;feature&rdquo; team working on the Manufacturing product.
We built features for the product in Spring and Angular.
It was a great learning experience in MVC web applications and software development process.
I had an amazing mentor on the team that really took me under his wing and I felt that I came up to speed really quickly because of this.</p>
<p>After getting the lay of the land and getting a little more comfortable, I started to feel like something was missing.
While the team that I worked on was great, the process in my company for integrating code and releasing to customers felt&hellip; disconnected.</p>
<p>I started reading articles and books about modern software practices and what we were doing didn&rsquo;t seem that close to these ideals.
While reading the DevOps Handbook, I started feeling the urge to be apart of this &ldquo;movement&rdquo;.
But when talking to those around me, I started to feel more alone, not many people seemed to care too much about these &ldquo;ideals&rdquo;.</p>
<h3 id="helping-on-the-pipeline">Helping On The Pipeline</h3>
<p>At the beginning of a PI (my company follows SAFe) last year, my team was asked to help out with the System Team for a couple of sprints.
This initiative was to move our existing pull request pipeline that ran on local hardware up to AWS.
I was extremely excited, finally I was able to get more hands on experience with something downstream of the features I was building.</p>
<p>The two sprints that we helped out was a whirlwind, but I loved it.
It was a rush to move everything up to the new environment because the current pipeline was burning down on slower local hardware.
But even though it was hectic, I felt at home solving these problems.</p>
<h3 id="moving-to-the-system-team">Moving to the System Team</h3>
<p>After our short time helping on the pipeline migration we went back to our normal work.
After a couple of sprints being back, I started to think about the experience a lot.
I really enjoyed the time working on those problems and I got a little bit of a better understanding of how my code moves down the stream.</p>
<p>When I heard that the System Team was looking to grow, I reached out to their manager to talk about it and get more information.
At first I wasn&rsquo;t sure what I wanted to do because I was so new in the industry and wasn&rsquo;t really sure which direction I wanted to go.
Also, I was a little nervous that the new position would require a lot more time commitment than my current position.
After some talks with the System Team manager and my wife, I decided to move to the System Team.</p>
<p>That was one of the best decisions I have made.</p>
<h3 id="being-a-pipeline-peep">Being a Pipeline Peep</h3>
<p>Being on the System Team (we call ourselves the Pipeline Peeps), has been an amazing journey.
I&rsquo;ve had the opportunity to work with some of the smartest people I have met, and I&rsquo;ve been right in the middle of everything in development at MasterControl.</p>
<p>This experience has given me a little more clarity on what I am passionate about in this industry.</p>
<h3 id="thanks">Thanks</h3>
<p>If you&rsquo;ve made it through this, I want to thank you.
It&rsquo;s probably not that interesting of stuff to anyone other than me.</p>
<p>But honestly, this blog is kinda mostly for me.
I have a desire to build things to mess around with things that interest me.
And I want to write about them.
If you find any of the things I post interesting, than that&rsquo;s just a bonus!!</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
